<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NewRecycleBuddy</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="recycleBuddy">RecycleBuddy</string>
    <string name="get_started_button">Get Started</string>
    <string name="recyclingbuddy_tree_icon">RecyclingBuddy Tree Icon</string>
    <string name="signup_title">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="login_title">Log In</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="signup">SignUp</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome!"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="community">Community</string>
    <string name="scan_here">Scan Here</string>
    <string name="info_hub">Info Hub</string>
    <string name="argument_key">my_info_topic\n</string>
    <string name="topic1_name">Recyclable Material Types</string>
    <string name="topic2_name">Triangle Recycling Codes</string>
    <string name="topic3_name">Recycling Process</string>
    <string name="topic4_name">Environmental Impacts</string>
    <string name="topic5_name">Recycling Facts</string>
    <string name="topic1_description">
    Paper and Cardboard Sources:\n
    • Newspapers, office paper, cardboard boxes.\n
    • Recycling: Shredded, pulped, and reformed into new paper products.\n\n
    Glass Sources:\n
    • Beverage bottles, food jars.\n
    • Recycling: Crushed, sorted by color, melted, and molded into new glass.\n\n
    Metals (Aluminum and Steel) Sources:\n
    • Aluminum cans, food cans, scrap metal.\n
    • Recycling: Shredded, melted, and remade, saving significant energy.\n\n
    Plastics Sources:\n
    • Water bottles (PET), milk jugs (HDPE).\n
    • Recycling: Sorted by type, cleaned, melted, and reformed into pellets.\n\n
    Sources: EPA, Earth911, National Geographic, Aluminum Association.
</string>

    <string name="topic2_description">
    Recycling codes, marked by triangle symbols with numbers, identify plastic types to aid in recycling. Here’s a summary:\n\n
    #1 PET (Polyethylene Terephthalate)\n
    • Common Uses: Water bottles, soft drink bottles.\n
    • Recyclability: Widely recycled, but typically only once.\n\n
    #2 HDPE (High-Density Polyethylene)\n
    • Common Uses: Milk jugs, detergent bottles.\n
    • Recyclability: Highly recyclable and durable.\n\n
    #3 PVC (Polyvinyl Chloride)\n
    • Common Uses: Pipes, shrink wrap.\n
    • Recyclability: Rarely recycled due to toxic chemicals.\n\n
    #4 LDPE (Low-Density Polyethylene)\n
    • Common Uses: Plastic bags, cling wrap.\n
    • Recyclability: Often not curbside recyclable but accepted at special facilities.\n\n
    #5 PP (Polypropylene)\n
    • Common Uses: Yogurt containers, straws.\n
    • Recyclability: Increasingly accepted for recycling.\n\n
    #6 PS (Polystyrene)\n
    • Common Uses: Styrofoam cups, takeout containers.\n
    • Recyclability: Difficult to recycle and usually not accepted.\n\n
    #7 Other (Miscellaneous Plastics)\n
    • Common Uses: Mixed plastics, reusable water bottles.\n
    • Recyclability: Not typically recycled; varies widely.\n\n
    Sources: EPA, Earth911, Plastic Pollution Coalition.
</string>


    <string name="topic3_description">
    The recycling process involves a few key steps:\n\n
    Collection and Transportation\n
    • Description: Materials are collected from homes, businesses, or drop-off locations and transported to recycling facilities.\n\n
    Sorting\n
    • Description: Materials are sorted by type (paper, plastic, glass, metals) using both manual and automated processes to ensure contamination is minimized.\n\n
    Cleaning and Processing\n
    • Description: Recyclables are cleaned to remove labels, adhesives, and contaminants. They are then processed (shredded, melted, or pulped) into raw forms like pellets or fibers.\n\n
    Manufacturing\n
    • Description: The processed raw materials are used to manufacture new products, which are then reintroduced to the market.\n\n
    Selling Recycled Products\n
    • Description: Recycled items are sold, completing the cycle and promoting further recycling.\n\n
    Sources: EPA, Earth911, National Geographic.
</string>
    <string name="topic4_description">
    Recycling has significant positive environmental impacts:\n\n
    Reduces Landfill Waste\n
    • Impact: Diverts waste from landfills, conserving space and reducing pollution from waste decomposition.\n\n
    Saves Energy and Natural Resources\n
    • Impact: Recycling materials like metals and paper uses less energy than producing new ones, conserving resources such as trees, water, and fossil fuels.\n\n
    Decreases Greenhouse Gas Emissions\n
    • Impact: Reduces emissions from production and landfill methane, helping mitigate climate change.\n\n
    Limits Pollution\n
    • Impact: Decreases air and water pollution from waste incineration and resource extraction.\n\n
    Conserves Wildlife Habitats\n
    • Impact: Reducing raw material extraction preserves natural habitats and biodiversity.\n\n
    Sources: EPA, National Geographic, Earth911.
</string>
    <string name="topic5_description">
        Here are some interesting recycling facts and statistics:\n\n
        • Plastic Waste: In 2021, only 5-6% of the 40 million tons of plastic waste generated in the U.S. was recycled.\n
        • Energy Savings: Recycling 10 plastic bottles can save enough energy to power a laptop for more than 25 hours.\n
        • Paper Recycling: Over 50 million tons of paper were recycled in 2021, achieving a 68% recycling rate.\n
        • Aluminum: Aluminum can be infinitely recycled with 95% less energy than creating new aluminum from raw materials.\n
        • Ocean Plastic: Between 75 and 199 million tons of plastic are currently in the oceans.\n
        • Economic Impact: The recycling industry in the U.S. supported 681,000 jobs and generated $37.8 billion in wages in 2020.\n
        • Cardboard: The recycling rate for corrugated cardboard was 91.4% in 2021. \n\n
        Sources: EPA, National Geographic, Earth911.
    </string>
    <string name="CategoryIntro1">Looking to learn more about recycling?</string>
    <string name="CategoryIntro2">Click any of the tabs below!</string>
</resources>